[Episode 11]
Mr. Shen.
Meng is locked up in prison.
I'm afraid they'll torture her.
Please help me.
Let me see her.
His Majesty has decreed
that no one is allowed to visit.
Meng, you poor thing.
You served the court
but ended up being imprisoned.
You go hungry and cold,
and you'll be tortured.
And no one is helping you.
- Enough.
- What should I do?
Enough.
Stop crying.
I'll make arrangements.
Really?
Thank you, Mr. Shen.
Don't go falling in love with me
over this.
You're overthinking it.
You're not up to my standards.
The most dashing and talented man
in the capital
is not good enough for you?
Thank you anyway.
No, don't thank me.
I'm doing this for Zhi Li's sake.
I'm here.
Everything's packed. Let's go.
Miss Meng will need all these.
I'm afraid the prison is too damp for her.
You're right, I left in a hurry
and forgot to prepare these.
I'm glad you care about Meng as much as I do.
Thank you.
Alright, no time to waste.
You two, visit Miss Meng.
I'll visit His Majesty.
- Let's go.
- Alright.
Excellent skills, Your Majesty.
Come on.
Your Majesty.
I'd rather not spar with you
when you're in this mood.
Your Majesty.
You can't take your anger out on us
over Meng Ting Hui.
Miss Meng.
This is your escape weapon.
This drug knocks out the jailers.
I'll lead you out of the prison.
Great minds think alike.
That's exactly my plan.
Meng, don't put up with this.
Just quit your job.
Anyway, I haven't spent too much
on the renovation of the Bofeng House branch.
Let's sublease it
and go back to our cozy lives in Shazhou.
My brother arranged for us to visit,
and you're scheming to break out
right in front of me.
Is that appropriate?
Given Mr. Shen's friendship with His Majesty,
he won't be implicated.
This is nonsense.
If I escape,
I'll become guilty for sure.
Put away the knockout drugs and blades.
But His Majesty went too far.
You achieved Triple First
and became the Director of Censorate.
He dismissed you just like that?
And he locked you up.
What happened to his word
being as good as gold?
It all depends on his mood.
If I had been there,
I would have scolded him
and torn him to shreds with my words.
Thank goodness you weren't there.
Otherwise, you'd be locked up with her.
We're here
to advise you to apologize to His Majesty.
Apologize to him?
No way.
She has no intention of repenting.
I knew she might go to the extreme
with cruel methods,
but I never imagined she would act on her own
without even informing me.
That's right.
A mere demotion
is already a sign of your mercy.
I think she needs at least thirty lashes
to learn this lesson.
Zhi Li asked you to come and mediate,
not to stir up trouble.
Miss Meng acted on impulse.
She didn't mean to offend you.
She didn't mean to?
So I made things difficult for her?
All the officials opposed my will.
I overrode all objections to appoint her.
But she didn't cherish it at all.
I entered officialdom to purge evil
and protect the people.
When those in power
care only for their own rise,
their path is paved with bones.
When the safety of the people is at stake,
how can I stand by and watch?
I saw how the Huxiao Gang
colluded with the authorities.
If I don't wipe them out,
how can I intimidate those in power?
If His Majesty
wanted someone conventional and obedient,
why did he appoint me
as Director of Censorate?
Exactly, Meng is right.
The law may be my guiding principle,
but this time, I'm siding with you.
I hope you will be reinstated.
And based on my understanding of His Majesty,
he doesn't really want to dismiss you.
Miss Meng, has His Majesty issued an edict?
Not yet.
Back in the palace,
she acted tough, then showed weakness,
and opened up to me.
She used every trick to get that position.
That's why I gave her a chance
and appointed her myself.
But she didn't know her place.
That's right.
She's taking advantage of your favor.
You trusted her with this post,
but she challenged you.
She's so reckless
and untamed.
She's not cut out for the imperial court.
You should send her back home
and never employ her again.
You think you're better than her?
I'm more competent as the Envoy of Customs.
Meng Ting Hui's appointment
was my careful decision.
I know if she's suitable for this job.
Then why did you lock her up?
I see.
Punishing Meng Ting Hui is just an act
to appease Lord Xu
and the other court officials.
You have really taken great pains
to protect Meng Ting Hui.
Who told you I was protecting her?
Without an edict,
you're still the Director of Censorate.
We can turn things around.
Aside from quelling public anger,
what else is His Majesty after?
Phoenix.
Where are you?
My darling.
Where did you fly off to?
I haven't seen you all day.
Master.
Have you seen Phoenix?
No, I haven't.
But there's a guest outside
who brought you a fine pastry.
He said you'd appreciate it once you saw it.
Can't you see I'm busy?
Put it down.
- Get out.
- But--
Go.
I'll check the doorway.
Look for it.
Seriously.
Phoenix.
My darling.
Where did you go?
Phoenix...
My darling!
Who did this to you?
My sweetheart.
My sweet...
[Kill]
Lord Xu wants to see you.
Let's go.
Lord Xu must be busy with state affairs.
Why would he ask to see a prisoner?
No more questions.
Naturally, Lord Xu has his reasons.
If you dare torture me,
His Majesty will surely find out.
His Majesty?
Do you really think His Majesty has time
to care about a prisoner like you?
Move.
Hands off me. I'll walk myself.
Don't try anything funny,
or you'll regret it.
Move.
How I love the scent of death.
Especially on a beauty.
Who are you?
Meng Ting Hui.
I remember every word
of the message you sent me.
Leader of the Huxiao Gang.
I only regret not hacking Lv Er to pieces
that very day.
But it's alright.
You're next.
I'd like to see
how a dead person gets revenge.
Lv Da, do it.
Master.
Lv Da, it's a trap. Retreat.
- Alright.
- After them.
Please don't be startled.
His Majesty sent us to protect you in secret.
By His Majesty's decree.
We're here to bring Minister Wan Kai in
for interrogation.
By His Majesty's decree.
We're here to bring Minister Wan Kai in
for interrogation.
Minister Wan.
Who did this to you?
Master.
Master, wait.
No, no.
I'm not making it.
Just go.
Nonsense. We go together.
Towards Changle Street.
Get them.
Your Majesty, the leader of the Huxiao Gang
has vanished.
The Shadow Guards
only found bloodstains on Changle Street.
He simply disappeared.
Changle Street.
Did Wan Kai say anything?
I arrived at the Wan Mansion
only to find Wan Kai dying
from a dagger wound.
He left this before he died.
If Wan Kai was nothing
but a disposable pawn to the Huxiao Gang,
the corruption in court
must be on a whole other level.
Your Majesty came to pick up a commoner.
I am flattered.
You have suffered.
For my aspiration,
anything is worthwhile.
Do you blame me?
I wouldn't dare.
But I would like to know the plan in advance
even as a commoner.
Or I may not act convincingly.
Stop calling yourself a commoner.
You may have acted recklessly
with the Huxiao Gang,
but your merits offset faults.
I hereby restore you to your position
as the Director of Censorate.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
The Huxiao Gang leader
indeed colluded with Wan Kai.
But he fled to Changle Street and vanished.
As for Wan Kai,
he died at home
just as I ordered his interrogation,
only leaving behind a note.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty used me as bait.
I understand that.
I hereby promise Your Majesty.
As long as I am in the Censorate,
I will see the Huxiao Gang case
through to the end.
But today, I am tired.
Please allow me to go back and rest.
I'll have the imperial physicians
treat the wound on your neck
to not leave a scar.
Let me take you back to the palace
and then send you home.
That's very kind of you.
But don't trouble the imperial physicians.
If it leaves a scar,
it will constantly remind me
to stay true to my original aspiration
and reflect on myself.
Huang Bo, escort Miss Meng back.
Ensure her safety.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Please allow me to go back alone.
I take my leave.
Will she keep hating me forever?
Your Majesty.
Miss Meng has a fiery temperament.
Give her some time.
I'm sure she will
understand your painstaking efforts.
Painstaking efforts?
She probably thinks
I am nothing but heartless.
It's Miss Meng.
- Miss Meng.
- Miss Meng is back.
Miss Meng.
We've waited for three days,
and you're finally back.
We're so happy.
This is great.
Miss Meng, your wound.
Yeah.
I scratched it myself.
I'm glad you're safe.
Has the Huxiao Gang been pestering you?
No.
Thanks to you, Miss Meng.
The authorities took over the land
snatched by the Huxiao Gang.
We have reburied our family's remains.
Thank you for helping us find justice.
That's right.
You suffered such injustice for us.
Thank you, Miss Meng.
Get up.
Cheng, get up.
Get up. All of you.
Get up.
You don't need to do this.
I merely did my job.
I'm just glad you're fine.
Miss Meng.
Here's a small token of appreciation.
Please accept it.
Take it back.
It was simply my duty.
- Take it back.
- Miss Meng.
Those bullies drove our entire family out,
turning us into homeless refugees.
Thanks to you, we're finally able to go home.
That's right.
I picked these fruits from the mountain.
Please accept them.
Miss Meng.
I heard you are from Shazhou.
I made this Shazhou dish.
You are too thin.
Please eat more.
That's right, Miss Meng.
Miss Meng.
- Get up.
- Miss Meng.
My daughter has been missing
for half a month.
The authorities say they're too busy.
Please help me.
Miss Meng.
I've also suffered great injustice.
Please seek justice for me.
Rest assured.
The Censorate
will definitely seek justice
for every one of you.
But I can't accept these things.
You've worked so hard to save up something
barely enough to sustain yourselves.
But I appreciate your kindness.
Thank you.
Miss Meng, we should be thanking you.
Now everyone knows
that you and the Censorate
are working for the people.
You are our pillar of support.
From now on, it's not just you protecting us.
We'll all protect you too.
Please accept these gifts.
Miss Meng, please accept them.
I really can't.
Thank you.
Take them.
Please accept them.
[Censorate]
I have repeatedly ordered the arrest
of the Huxiao Gang,
but it still hasn't been done.
Are they exceptionally resourceful,
or is someone secretly helping them?
I understand Your Majesty's worry.
The Ministry of Justice needs a leader
after Wan Kai's death.
I suggest we let the Vice Minister of War
take over for now
and investigate the Huxiao Gang case.
I have
fully entrusted the case to the Censorate.
As for the candidate for Minister of Justice,
I have someone in mind as well.
Your Majesty.
May I ask whom you intend to appoint?
And may I ask
why Wan Kai summoned Meng Ting Hui
on your order
and then dropped dead in his mansion?
Your Majesty, I swear on my life.
I had no idea what Wan Kai had done.
Nor was it by my order.
I have political disagreements
with Meng Ting Hui,
but I have no intention to harm her.
Please see this clearly.
You say it lightly, Lord Xu.
Wan Kai made a huge mess,
and yet you knew nothing.
If your dog bit someone,
can you claim innocence?
How dare you!
I'm talking to His Majesty.
How dare you jest and interrupt?
I'm just telling the truth.
If you are innocent,
why would you be afraid of my jokes?
Shen Zhi Shu,
show the Left Chancellor some respect.
It's just that
the Ministry of War was trading arms.
The Ministry of Rites
was involved in exam fraud.
Even the Minister of Justice
colluded with gangs
against the people.
You've overseen the six ministries for years.
The claim of ignorance is probably not enough
to get you out of it.
I have failed in my duty.
I ask to resign from my official post
and retire to my hometown.
Your Majesty, the late emperor
assigned Lord Xu to this job.
He's been aiding you
for over ten years.
Now, even in his seventies,
he still rises at the Yin hour
to review memorials
and comes to court at the Mao hour.
I hope Your Majesty will punish him lightly
for the sake of your ties.
Your Majesty.
The law bends to human sentiment.
To punish Lord Xu severely
may seem disheartening to the old ministers.
A feigned retreat to gain ground. Brilliant.
You are forcing His Majesty
to choose between law and human sentiment.
Lord Xu,
you are a meritorious official
of three reigns of our Ning Empire,
and a pillar of the state
with great service.
How could I truly punish you severely?
But you have advanced in years.
I should personally attend to the affairs
of the six ministries.
I won't trouble you to labor on my behalf.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Yes!
The Bofeng House opens today.
Please come in.
Please come in. Mind the steps.
[Bofeng House]
What a lousy restaurant.
How dare they steal my business
on their very first day?
My lady.
I got information.
The owner of Bofeng House is Yan Fu Zhi,
the sworn sister of Miss Meng.
They've stayed at our inn before.
So it's those two.
I knew it was a collusion
between officials and merchants.
Shun.
Keep an eye on them.
I'll catch them slipping up sooner or later.
[Chunman House]
Ms. Yan, no need to see us further.
Gentlemen,
this is our exclusive Shazhou candied fruit.
Paired with apricot skin tea,
it cuts the grease.
Please kindly accept it.
How thoughtful.
We will definitely come every day
and try all the Shazhou delicacies.
That would be wonderful.
Farewell.
Take care.
Ms. Yan, wipe your drool.
They've gone far.
Mr. Shen, which lady did you bring today?
Your...
Ms. Yan.
Wake up.
This is a bit exaggerated.
Don't make me give you mouth-to-mouth.
In your dreams.
I heard Bofeng House is opening today.
We came to show support.
No need for formalities. Just call me He Du.
Where is she?
Right upstairs.
Mr. He, this way, please.
Mind the steps.
Ms. Yan.
Why favor one customer over another?
It feels like
you've moved the desert
right into the capital.
Every corner is scenic, a world of its own.
Interesting.
On Changle Street,
how can we keep our guests
without something unique?
The Wangyou Pavilion is reserved for Meng.
All other private rooms are for guests
who spend over 100 taels per visit.
With your capability, Mr. Shen,
you'll soon have a room of your own.
Meng.
Your Majesty.
You really bring this pretty boy
everywhere you go.
Your Majesty, Yin Qing
is my colleague from the Censorate,
not some pretty boy.
I am handling a case.
Naturally, Yin Qing will follow me around.
Miss Meng.
His Majesty meant it as a compliment.
Handling a case?
You're handling a case here?
The Huxiao Gang leader
was last seen on Changle Street.
If I were to search openly,
it may alert them.
Bofeng House sits on Changle Street.
A perfect spot for watching.
I've made this room my base of operations.
Your Majesty.
Nian.
So you rushed out of the door
to do odd jobs for Zhi Li.
It's not odd jobs.
Nian is helping with official business.
Your Majesty.
Miss Meng has been worried
about the investigation.
I drew this based on her description.
Although we only
have a pair of eyes as a clue,
we will follow Miss Meng's plan
and thoroughly search Changle Street.
I know all the noble families.
So I'll watch
the high-end tea houses and herbal shops.
Yin Qing is good with ladies.
So he'll watch all the cosmetics shops,
music houses, and brothels.
As for Miss Meng.
She told me she grew up
dealing with all sorts of people.
So she'll watch all the gambling dens
and private banks.
Your Majesty.
Do we need to keep you updated
and wait for your approval
to proceed?
Not really.
Then what brings you here, Your Majesty?
Regarding Wan Kai's death,
Xu Ting looked honest
and sounded genuinely indignant.
The message Wan Kai left behind
remains unclear.
I need you
to thoroughly investigate the Huxiao Gang,
and find the person behind them.
I will look into this
with the utmost diligence.
This is a secret remedy for removing scars.
His Majesty got it for you.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
But I have
applied Yin Qing's scar removal cream.
My wound is already healing.
Your Majesty.
Miss Meng doesn't need it anymore.
Miss Meng means to say
that the two creams
might cancel each other out
if mixed.
Are you saying
your medicine is more effective than mine?
No, no.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
No more business talk.
Actually, Mr. He came here
just to enjoy some authentic lamb noodles.
Meng.
You've been learning to make lamb noodles.
So it was for Mr. He.
Mr. He, look forward
to the authentic lamb noodles.
I...
- I did not.
- Let's go.
I have an appointment to study painting
with Master.
Then I'll handle the tasks
Miss Meng assigned.
I'll let you enjoy your drink.
Only Lord Gu
can make you abandon Nian and me.
Zhi Li, let me see you out.
Only Zhi Li can make you abandon me.
Your Majesty, Mr. Shen.
I just remembered,
Miss Meng also has tasks for me.
I take my leave.
Your Majesty's cream works better.
Why did everybody leave?
Meng.
Mr. He came to Bofeng House in person
and asked for lamb noodles.
You think he regrets punishing you
and wants to ease things with you?
His Majesty's mind is hard to fathom.
We must not speculate recklessly.
Let alone flatter ourselves.
You're right. He's the emperor, after all.
You must not talk back to him again.
Otherwise, he could have us executed.
I didn't talk back to him.
Sure, if you say so.
Meng, listen.
Tell him you made this bowl of lamb noodles.
Fu Zhi, deceiving His Majesty
is a capital offense.
What should we do?
Yan Fu Zhi.
Listen to me.
You sprinkled these scallions.
So basically,
you made this bowl of lamb noodles.
I just helped you a little.
We're not deceiving anyone.
Meng!
Meng.
Meng, have you lost it?
Looks like I'm the one
who made the noodles now.
[Bofeng House]
I still remember that bowl of lamb noodles
you bought me.
So you're here to collect a debt.
What do you think?
Are you happy with all these dishes?
Isn't this a bit too extravagant?
Don't worry, you're not spending a penny.
It's on Ms. Yan.
So you're putting it on Miss Yan's tab,
while claiming to buy me dinner.
You're mistaken.
I've prepared a big surprise for you.
Miss Situ has arrived.
There she is.
Mr. Shen, Mr. He.
Thank you for inviting me. Nice to meet you.
Miss Situ, what a pleasure.
So this is the surprise you prepared.
Mr. He.
Here comes the lamb noodles made by Meng.
Come on.
Enjoy.
Mr. He, please enjoy.
Everyone is here.
Miss Meng, Ms. Yan,
let me introduce you.
This is the legendary--
Situ Xue.
Miss Meng, you know Miss Situ too?
Mr. He has mentioned you. I truly admire you.
You flatter me, Miss Meng.
I've heard so much about you.
It's such a great honor to meet you today.
My cousin specially invited Miss Situ here
to celebrate the grand opening.
Thank you, Mr. He.
You must be Ms. Yan of the Bofeng House.
Yes, that's me.
I've arranged for some musicians
to celebrate the grand opening.
I brought you a golden qilin
as a welcoming gift.
I wish you a thriving business.
Your presence brings light
to our humble establishment.
There's no need for gifts.
Zhao Cai, put it away.
Don't just stand there.
Try our signature dishes.
I didn't expect to have
the real...
Miss Situ, please try some.
You don't socialize much.
Thanks to my cousin's hospitality...
It's nothing.
Everyone, please enjoy.
Don't you like spicy food?
What's this today?
Mr. He, warm soup is good for the stomach.
Is the lamb soup good?
Yes.
It's amazing.
It's just like the one in Shazhou.
Spicy and fierce.
Have some more then.
You could eat two bowls of noodles
back in Shazhou.
Have some buckthorn honey juice
to soothe the spice.
Miss Meng, how can I repay
your warm hospitality?
You jest, Mr. He.
You're thoughtful enough to invite Miss Situ.
What does my bowl of noodles amount to?
I've only met Miss Situ a few times.
I was quite surprised that she graced us
with her presence today.
Ms. Yan and I
both do business on Changle Street.
And I've heard so much about Miss Meng,
wishing to get to know her.
That's why I came.
Let me take this opportunity
to propose a toast.
How can the ruler of an empire
be so vindictive?
You brought Situ Xue
to mock my clumsy imitation in Shazhou.
I can't defend myself at all.
You've really done me in.
It seems they are not
simply ruler and minister.
I thought you could be reliable for once.
You can't do anything right.
Fine wine, delicious food,
and beauties by my side.
Let's drink to our hearts' content.
It's a rare opportunity for us to gather.
But I have duties to attend to. Excuse me.
Meng, are you alright? I'll go with you.
No need. Miss Situ is a rare guest.
Stay and have a few more drinks with her.
Please carry on.
I also have work to do. Please enjoy.
Cousin.
Ms. Yan, Mr. Shen.
I also have work to do at my music house.
I take my leave.
Such good Shaosanbai wine.
Why did everyone leave?
Ms. Yan, let's drink.
Wait.
You haven't served the tribute wine, right?
Mr. Shen, I'll get it for you right away.
Yeah, drink yourself to death.
Mr. Shen, here's the tribute wine.
Have more. But don't throw up.
Cheers.
Take care, sir.
[Xingrong Gambling House]
This way.
Most gangs run gambling dens.
Most gambling dens are full of cheats.
The Huxiao Gang can't be an exception.
Stop.
No unauthorized entry.
Why can't I go upstairs?
Please forgive us.
This is our rule.
You must win 10,000 taels to go upstairs.
- You are--
- I'm the dealer, Gui.
I don't recall seeing you before.
Is this your first time here?
Newcomers get ten taels of betting credit
as a welcome gift.
Your boss knows how to run a business.
Quite a figure in the underworld, I suppose?
You're very sharp.
Our boss is surnamed Hao.
All the fellows honor him as Mr. Hao.
Mr. Hao.
Alright, I'll try my luck today.
This way.
[Small, Big]
Miss, just a second.
I'll invite someone to join you.
Third Master, we have a new guest.
Would you like to join in?
Why would I gamble with a woman?
Wait.
Mr. Wang, join us for a game.
- A lady? Not interested.
- Wait.
I'll join you.
Sir, please have a seat.
Mr. He, you're in quite the mood today.
Since no one else would play with you,
I figured I'd step in, reluctantly.
In that case,
let's get started.